Accounting and Reporting of Defect Opportunities
Welcome back to this session on defect opportunities. What we would like to do,
is to advance this concept one stage further,
by considering the metric defects per opportunity,
as a simple ratio. Now, to understand that I'm going to create some slots.
Let's say, three simple slots. And those slots belong to the numerator.
So, I’m going to form a ratio here of some slots
in the numerator
and some slots in the denominator.
So, we got denominator slots, numerator slots.
And, every slot in the denominator is an event.
It's the occurrence of an interface between
the process capability and the design requirement.
The upper and lower specification. In other words, it's the marriage
between the process and the design.
If the marriage occurred,
then we would have a one in this box.
In other words, there is a production opportunity.
If the process cycles once, then it creates,
it creates an outcome. Now, that outcome
could be one of two possible conditions.
It could either be a zero, or it could be a one.
In other words, if it's a one, then it's a defect.
That interface was not good. It didn't pass.
It wasn't up to standard. It wasn't up to par. A defect was created.
If it's a zero, then it was yield.
So, if it's zero. It's a green. It's in the spec boundary.
If it's a one, it's out here in these tails. So, the first thing is, did we create it? Yes.
See, that's the first question, did we create it?
Yes equals one, no equals zero.
In this case, it’s a one so we did create it. Now we say,
if yes, was it good? That has two possible conditions 0, 1.
So, we can get a 0,1 here, 0,1 here.
Now, let's suppose on the first cycle of the process we did in fact create a CTQ,
a critical to quality characteristic. We did create it so there's a 1. And now let's suppose,
strictly for the sake of argument, that it was not defective. So, we put in a zero.
Now let's suppose that we go back on the second cycle of the process,
the process cycles again.
And let's suppose, that we created another CTQ, a replication of the first CTQ.
We’ve got production going on. So, we made the first CTQ. We’ve made that CTQ again.
But this time, aw-oh, we had a failure. So, we get a 1.
And now let's suppose, on the third cycle, we left the material out of the machine.
And so, it didn't create the CTQ. Therefore, since it’s a zero here, it has to be a zero there.
You can't create a defect if you never made the CTQ. That simple.
Now, let's take a look across the numerator here. We’re going to come over here.
How many defects were made? 0, 1, 0. 1.
How many opportunities were created? 2.
So, what's our defects per opportunity?
Defects per opportunity equals 1 over 2, which is equal to .50.
In this case, 50%
of the opportunities we’re creating were defective.
Now, what we do not want to do is this.
We do not want to say, well, the process cycled three times. One, two, three.
See, here’s the process cycles. Cycle one. Cycle two, Cycle three.
One, plus one, plus one, equals three.
So, the defects per opportunity is one over three. Not one over two. Wrong.
We’re not measuring defects per process cycle.
We are measuring defects per product opportunity, per CTQ.
So once again,
a defect opportunity is anything that we regularly measure and report.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.